Resume

View the Project on GitHub at https://github.com/

Myles J. Johnson-Gray

mjayegray@gmail.com | 302-670-9580

Education

- University of Delaware (Aug 2015-May 2017)
 - Master of Science in Computer Science
 - GPA: 3.2
- Delaware State University (Aug 2011-May 2015)
 - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Magna Cum Laude
 - GPA: 3.5

Summary

Creative and adaptable software engineer (with 5+ years of experience) offering proficiency in scripting and object-oriented programming, as well as strong teamwork and communication skills. Seeking new opportunities to utilize my skills towards creating meaniningful software.

Specific interests include: artificial intelligence, user interface design, music.

Technical Skills

Languages/Frameworks

C++, Java, Python, HTML/Javascript, SQL, .NET.

Mathematics

Calculus, probability, statistics, trigonometry, discrete mathematics, linear algebra, and theory of computation.

Systems/Software:

Wireshark, VirtualBox, Eclipse, GitHub, Rational Clearcase, JIRA, Jenkins, Confluence, Froglogic Squish, Office 365/SharePoint/Power Automate, SmartBear Collaborator, and OpenGL.

Relevant Experience

Raytheon Technologies - Software Engineer II (Patriot Tools Team, Patriot Maintenance & Diag Team)

Lawrence, Massachusetts, USA (May 2018 - Present)

- Developed, facilitated the delivery of, and performed regression/integration testing on maintenance software (Ada/C++) for Patriot Missle System.
- Produced in-house scripting and frontend tools (Python, .NET, PHP, Perl) to improve development and testing efficiency of engineering teams.
- Responsible for introducing DevSecOps and agile tools (JIRA, Jenkins, Collaborator, GitHub) and concepts to outdated engineering product groups.
- Secret Clearance from U.S. Department of Defense

Delaware State University - Undergraduate Researcher

Dover, Delaware, USA (Feb 2012 - May 2015)

- Assisted in the software development of NeRvolver, a computational intelligence-based system (using evolutionary algorithms and fuzzy logic) for automated construction, analysis, and tuning of neuronal models.
- Implemented the NSGA-2 and END_VEGA algorithms in C++, and performed an empirical algorithm analysis on both algorithms applied to neuronal modeling.
- Implemented statistical functions for analysis of neuronal data.
- Contributed in a lab research team: committed code to a code base, participated in lab meetings, and orally presented our work at several conferences.

National Institute of Health - International Summer Research Intern

Ningbo University, Ningbo, China (May 2012 - July 2012)

- Participated in courses covering knowledge of various data mining techniques, including clustering, classification methods, and decision trees.
- Developed decision trees, predicting several NBA player shot selections and results based on a number of in-game critieria.
- Prepared an oral and poster presentation of my work at a local symposium.

Summer Research Intern

Clemson University, South Carolina, USA (May 2014 - July 2014)

- Developed a graph ontology based system for keyword extraction of biomedical publications in Java.
- Prepared an oral and poster presentation for a local symposium.
- Participated in a number of courses covering SSH, operating systems, and object-oriented programming fundamentals.

Github Repositories

Each bullet below contains a hyperlink mapping to the respective repository location.

- Constructed a character prediction system using bigrams to generate predictions for a dynamic AAC keyboard.
- Implemented shading, reflection/refraction, bump mapping, model loading, and flocking schemas in graphics projects using OpenGL.
- Created a Perl program to simulate the mutation and alignment of amino acid sequences using a PAM matrix.
- Built and tested a decision tree class on Wisconsin breast cancer data.
- Developed a Forward Chaining Knowledge Base of Restaurants for Main Street (Newark, Delaware).

- Designed a stock market QA system using sentiment analysis.
- Produced a system that uses Hidden Markov Models through viterbi training to find the most likely path for given genome sequences.

AUTHORED PUBLICATIONS

- "Hybridization of multi-objective evolutionary algorithms and fuzzy control for automated construction, tuning, and analysis of neuronal models" peer-reviewed abstract, Patel P., Johnson-Gray M., Forren E., Malik A., and Smolinski T.G., BMC Neuroscience 14(Suppl 1):P369, 2013.
- "NeRvolver: a computational intelligence-based system for automated construction, tuning, and analysis of neuronal models" peer-reviewed abstract, Forren E., Johnson-Gray M., Patel P., and Smolinski T.G., BMC Neuroscience 13(Suppl 1):P36, 2012.

SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

- Computational Neuroscience (CNS) Conference (Atlanta 2012, Paris 2013)
- Annual Biomedical Research Conference for Minority Students (ABRCMS) (San Jose 2012, Nashville 2013, San Antonio 2014)
- Emerging Researchers National (ERN) Conference (Washington D.C 2014)

Project maintained by **gitmyles**Hosted on GitHub Pages — Theme by **orderedlist**